Guide to the William Russell Dudley Papers SC0558
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Class materials, lecture notes, and manuscript articles
  - " Aspects of our native ... " manuscript of an address before Floral Society on colors of California vegetation (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Distribution of Trees and Shrubs on Searsville Ridge [now Jasper Ridge] - 13 page manuscript report, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - The forests of California Manuscript article (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - [California forests] manuscript text and notes for a talk or paper (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Concerning the Anthers and the Pollination of Zostera latifolia, manuscript article (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Date Palm - Tuesday evening address at Stanford University 1899 or 1900 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Forests and Forest-Trees of Santa Cruz County, 1902 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Insects Injurious to Young Trees, typescript (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Native trees and shrubs of the Big Basin [mss and tss versions] circa 1901 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Next Step in Forestry, lecture at Stanford, Feb. 23, 1900 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Progress in Forestry (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - "The Sequoia of the Sierras," American Forestry Association - manuscript text/article, 1900 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Zonal article for Sierra Club - data (notes, lists) for (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - "The Vitality of Sequoia Gigantea," lecture before Columbia college alumni (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Bound reprints, including annotated "Cayuga Flora." (Box 20)
- Field Notes and Research Notes
  - "Catalogue of the Gramineae of the Cayuga Valley," 1883; "Catalogue of the Vascular Cryptogamia of the Cayuga Valley," 1891; and a typed list of flora, 1883/1891 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Notes: unlabeled list of flora (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Notes on Sequoia Gigantea (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Notes on Mt. Whitney trail [mss copy of a portion of notes by J. N. LeConte (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Botanical Excursions beyond the Santa Cruz peninsula and Bay region, 1893-1902 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Notes, 1885 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - List of San Diego plants, 1895 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Atwells, Kahneah, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Notes: Sequoia groves, north of King's River, nd. (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Porterville area maps (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Township plot maps with notes (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Notes: Zostera / Phyllospadix, with illustrations (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Carex notes (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - List of Mosses Studied at Cornell University, undated with two clippings 1878, and 1 page of a letter to Dudley 1880, 1878/1880 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous undated (notes, illustration, clipping) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Work on genera (1): menispermacea; berberidaceae; symphiacea (?); sarraceniaceae; papaveraceae; fumariacea; caryophliacea (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Work on genera (2): sonchus; [illegible]; rubiaceae; valerianacea; dipsaceae; solidago; mikania; eupatorium; bellis; aster (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Work on genera (3): portulacaceae; hypericaceae; capparidaceae; polygalaceae; cruciferae (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Work on genera (4): bignoniaea (?); [remaining 2 subset titles are illegible] (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Work on genera (5): borras; gentranaceae; solan; [illegible]; orobanchacea; lentibulacea (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Work on genera (6): magnoliaceae; primulaceae; plantagenaceae; oliaceae; apocynaceae; asclipradaceae (?); lobeliaceae (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Work on genera (7): campanulaceae; ericaceae; polernoniaceae; hydro; convol (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Work on genera (8): ranunculaceae; malvaceae; tiliaceae; linaceae;geraniaceae; rutaceae; illicineae (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Work on genera (9): celastraceae; rhamnaceae; vitaceae; sapindaceae; anacardiaceae; leguminosae (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Work on genera (10): rosaceae; crassulaceae; saxifragaceae (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Work on genera (11): droseraceae; hamamelaceae; haloragrae; melastomaceae; lystraceae; onagraceae; cucurbitaceae; ficordeae; umbelliferae (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Work on genera (12): enigeron; antennaria; anaphalis (DC); gnaphalium; inula; polymnia; ambrosia; xanthium; zinnia; heliopsis; rudbeckia (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Work on genera (13): helianthus; coreopsis; bidems; helenium; anthruis;achillaea; chrysanthemum; tanacetum; Artemisia; tussilago; petacites (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Work on genera (14): senecio; erschthites; arctium; cnicus; centaurea;cichorium; tragopgon; hieracium; prenanthea; taraxacum; lactuca (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Sharon estate - notes on trees 1894 and undated, 1894/undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Notes on the Trees of North America (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - List of conifers, Genera and Species (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Graminiae - notes (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Rosales - notes, lists, 1896 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous lists, 1870-1879 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Notes: California plants; C. G. Pringle, Central Mexico; cactacea; loco weeds (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Notes: European; 2 pages on Salicaceae (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Notes: " lists of plants already exchanged or given away " and " exchanges fungi " (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Notes: Southwestern plants; Salvia; Ramona; and miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Exchanges; and miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Dudley collections [plant and where collected], 1874-1881 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Dudley collections [plant and where collected], 1882-1891 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Laws of geographical distribution (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Dicotylidones notes (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Notes: fungi, graminiae, and others (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Notes: juncus, panicum, and others (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - List of conifers and other notes (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Notes on distribution; coniferae of the world (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Notes on genera: Mynacaceae; Populus; Amarant; Aecidiomycetes; and others (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Notes: forest, Pinus Mexico, Yucca, Acacia (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Trees, Plants to be collected, Economic Botany, Palms, Abies (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Muscineai (1) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Notes: Muscineai (2) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Notes: fungi (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Notes: entomosporium, bacteria, disease of mulberry, grasses, tomato diseases, ustilaga, other diseases, yeast (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Notes: intracycliea, cornaceae, araliaceae, spermaphytes (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Notes: fungi (2) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Notes: schizomycetes (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Notes III (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Notes IV - VIII (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Notes: Notes IX - XIV (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Notes: Salix (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Notes: Notes 2-19 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Notes: Notes 20-37 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Notes: communities of plants (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Notes: conifers (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Notes: miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Notes: forests (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Notes: forests (2) (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Notes: alnus and others (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Notes: ustilagineae (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Notes: ustilagineae (2) (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Notes: geographical distribution of conifers (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Notes: uredinaleae (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Notes: aecidiomycetes (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Notes: List of the coraiferae of California (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Notes: compo sitae (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Notes: tetracyllicae (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Notes: umbelliferae (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Notes: cactaceae (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Notes: myraceae (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Notebook #65 [plant collecting in area of Ocean A venue - Merced Lake in San Francisco], Oct. 1908 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Notebook #68 [plant collecting in area of Glenwood and Seabright], June 1909 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Notebook #71 [plant collecting in Palo Alto area, Paso Robles, Gilroy and other places], 1909-1910 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Notes in regard to work at Bloomington, 1880 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Index cards in regard to locations in New York State, 1884-1885 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - List of plants studied at Cornell, 1885 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - F. V. Coville collections in New York (determined by Dudley) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Field notes from Lackawanna and Wyoming Valleys in New York, June/September 1886 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Scranton notes, 1889 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Field notes (New York), 1890 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Field notes Ararat Summit, 1891 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Field notes on C. O. Thurston's Herb., 1892 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Excursion itinerary, June 1893 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Field notes Mendocino County Sept., circa 1894 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Excursions [mainly the itinerary], 1894-1895 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Plants from San Juan Baptiste Hills and Madrone Springs, May-June 1895 [includes brochure from Madrone Springs Health Resort] (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Field notes Pescadero Creek and Palo Alto estate (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Catalogue of negatives taken in the Sierra Nevada Mts. summers of 1895 and 1896, 1895/1896 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Excursion notes Banff, Canada, Palmdale to Sta. Barbara, June-July 1896 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Notes and sketches Kaweahs - Sequoia, July-August 1896 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Santa Cruz mountains Feb. 1893, Mar.-Oct. 1896, May 1897, June & Nov. 1899, 1893/1896/1897/1899 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Notes: Pescadero, Butano Creek, 1896-1897 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Porterville and Daunt, March 1897 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Elevation notes, July 11-17, 1897 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Notes: Upper Kern to Mt. Whitney `, July-August 1897 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Notes: to Mrs. Murphy's on Pescadero Creek, down Butano Creek to little Butano Creek, December 1897-1898 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Notes: San Benito County - New Idria, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Notes: Mt. Low summit, San Gabriel Park, 1899-1900 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Notes: Fresno, Visalia, Porterville to Milo and Dillon's Forest, April 1900 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Notes: Page Mill and Montebello Roads, List of trees and shrubs, April 14, 1900 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Truckee to Summit, via Donner Summit (Salix collections), June 1900 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Notes: Monterey, Nacimiento, March 1901 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Notes: Species noted in Notebooks I, II, III, Santa Lucia mountains (1 of 2), 1901 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Notes: Species noted in Notebooks I, II, III, Santa Lucia mountains (2 of 2), 1901 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Notes: Redwood Retreat - Gilroy, Little Uvas, Mt. Madonna, 1901 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Notes: Lorna Prieta Peak, October 1902 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Notes: Monterey, Huckleberry Hill (for Pacific Imp. Company), October 1902 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Notes: Big Basin with Mr. Middleton, 1902, with Ernest and Walter Fisher, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Carmel, Nacimiento (Monterey County) Abies venusta, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Notes: Flood estate, Menlo Park, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Santa Cruz via Pajaro, return via Felton, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Perrnanente Creek, July 1903 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Notes: Boulder Creek, Big Basin, Felton, Zeyante, Los Trancos Creek, Goat Ranch and south, April 1904 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Notes: ponds, Iron Ridge (Connecticut?), July 1904 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Notes: San Bruno Hills, Bakers Beach, San Francisco sand dunes, Mountain View ravine, September-December 1904 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Notes: Carmel River, Pacific Improvement Company's reservoir, June 1979 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Notes: San Mateo - Homestead 650' Stanford, Woodside, May-June 1906 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Notes: Murphys, Big Trees, San Anton Falls, August 1906 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Notes: [near Los Gatos?], May-June 1908 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Notes: W. W. Wagener collection (mycologist) - Plumas County near Quincy, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Guilford undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Notes: Atherton's pond (New York), Lehigh Pond, etc., undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Portland to Mt. Hood, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Notes: equipment lists, undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Notes: miscellaneous, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Notes: Santa Cruz Mountains redwoods 1900-01 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Itinerary and field notes, mostly California, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Meares Mexican boundary plants, list of localities copied from the notebooks, 1892-1894 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Fragments [1 sheet - a list] (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Dudley's dissecting tools (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Lilia (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Notes: Hydrochar. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Notes: Orchidian. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Notes: Inid (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Amaryll (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Notes: Dioscoreaciai (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Notes: Smilax (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Pontederia (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Notes: Typhae (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Notes: Araciai (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Notes: Lemnacia (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Notes: Alisma (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Notes: Naiad (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Notes: Betulaceae (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Notes: Carpuliferae (?) (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Notes: Piperaceae (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Euphorbia (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Notes: Laurineae and others (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Urtic and Platan (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Notes: Triglandeae (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Notes: Chenopod (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Notes: Phytolac (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Notes: Polygon (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Notes: Orobanchaceae; Compositae; Carex (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Notes: Potamogeton (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Notes: Conifers and possibly others (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Bolander and others (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Notes: assorted (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Notes: suggestions for investigations (Box 18, Folder 29)
- Oversize publications and maps
  - Publications: issues of Los Angeles Saturday Post 1902 and an article from Town Talk ( " A One Hundred Day Trip in the Sierra Nevadas " by T. P. Lukens), Feb. 6, 1897 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Maps: Sierra Nevada (including several by J. N. LeConte), 1893-1903 and undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Maps: west side Sierra Nevada (mostly Placer County) undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Maps: California (counties, Oakland, and others) 1899-1902 and undated, 1899-1902/undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Map: Oregon state, 1889 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Maps: New York (Wyoming & Lackawanna Valleys which cross into Pennsylvania), 1884-1902 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Maps: United States, 1876-1937 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Maps: World (Seat of War in Africa 1899, Mindanao, Philippines 1902), 1899/1902 (Box 19, Folder 8)